MANAGER OPERATIONS ADMINISTRATION

Professional Summary

High-performing and versatile Business Operations Manager experienced in financial analysis, strategic management and process improvement within a regulated healthcare/pharmaceutical environment. Specialization in managing, analyzing and containing overhead costs, making business-sound decisions and providing exceptional customer service. A strong leader who possesses a high degree of integrity, compassion and an outstanding work ethic with proven abilities in team building, coaching and development.

Highlights

- Policy decision-maker, excelling in implementation and enforcement
- Detail-oriented project manager
- Confident and persuasive communicator with dynamic energy
- Motivational and encouraging coach and mentor
- Sharp leader with a clear understanding of financial operations
- Cross-functional team leader

Skills

Specialized skills in the following competencies that are an invaluable asset to any healthcare organization:

- Management of material, financial and personnel resources
- Strategic planning
- · Operations analysis
- Financial reporting, analysis and planning
- Cost-benefit analysis
- · Facilities Management

Professional Experience

Manager Operations Administration 04/2014 to Current Weidner Covington, WA

Worked directly with the Executive Director, Operations (now SVP, Operational Excellence) in a newly created position.

- Held accountability for company-wide Facilities, Engineering, EH&S and Corporate Real Estate operational expenditures and analysis.
- Maintained Corporate Global Real Estate Dashboard and profile.
- Cross-functional team member of company M&A and integration activities.
- Administrative operations project manager for site closure of the St. Louis offices.

Manager, Facilities Business Operations 04/2013 to 04/2014 Forest Pharmaceuticals, Inc. City, STATE

Restructured and harmonized US Facilities' budgeting, tracking and analysis process. Managed 15 cost centers for 11 buildings; accountable for over \$17 million in operating expenses per year.

- Developed and managed annual operating budgets for St. Louis, Cincinnati and Long Island sites.
- Captured and analyzed spending trends to provide accurate forecasts, provide leadership with supportive data and eliminate or reduce wasteful spending.
- Served on various leadership teams for submittal and decision-making for capital and operational budget items.
- Developed and created cost-benefit analysis (CBAs) for a variety of project work and overhead costs decisions.
- Held accountability for operating and capital expenses, monthly analysis and fiscal planning.
- Project manager for operating and capital renovation projects.
- Oversaw various departmental reviews and strategy initiatives; reorganized and streamlined department's administrative operations and activities.
- OSHA 10-Hour Certification.

Associate Manager, Facilities Business Operations 12/2008 to 04/2013 Forest Pharmaceuticals, Inc. City, STATE

Accountable for St. Louis and Cincinnati departmental business operations and site administrative/soft facility services for St. Louis location; managed 4 employees that performed administrative support for site.

- Developed and managed annual operating budgets for St. Louis and Cincinnati sites.
- Accountable for operating and capital expenses, monthly analysis and fiscal planning for St. Louis and Cincinnati sites.
- Analyzed departmental spending trends to question expenses; implemented cost-saving strategies and ensured optimal financial performance.
- Created report and managed a team that provided executive leadership with monthly and quarterly reporting packages to analyze global team activities, projects, and spending.
- Managed 30 service contracts per year. Created SOWs and negotiated rates and terms.
- Managed office service requests, office moves, space utilization and planning.

Branch Rental Manager/Rental Sales Rep/Management Trainee 03/2006 to 12/2008 Penske Truck Leasing, Inc. City, STATE

Branch Manager (Rental) 2008

- Held P&L accountability for \$1.6 million in peak annual revenue generated from rentals of
- 400+ units and \$18 million in assets for 3 locations in the St. Louis metro area; managed
- 5 union employees performing rental operations and sales activities.

Sales Representative (Rental) 2007 â€" 2008

- Marketed rental fleet, maintenance, and lease capabilities throughout the greater Syracuse and eventually St. Louis areas.
- Rental Sales Honor Roll

Management Trainee 2006 - 2007

- Held rotational assignments to learn every aspect of business; rental operations/reservations, logistics, financial administration, business development/sales, customer service, and truck maintenance.
- Northeast Area Dedication to Excellence Customer Service Award

Manager In Training 06/2005 to 12/2005 Finish Line, Inc. City, STATE

• Generated sales, managed profitability & loss prevention, and provided exceptional customer service.

Education and Training

MBA: Healthcare Management 2016 Walden University City, State

BACHELOR OF ARTS: Organizational Communication Keuka College City, State